Ronson's down.
He needs a medical evac.
Where is it? Is it there?
- Oh, the drive is gone.
- Are you sure?
It's gone. Give me a minute.
They must have it.
Get after them.
- I'm stabilising Ronson.
- We don't have the time.
- I have to stop the bleeding.
- Leave him!
Have you got him?
He is in the black Audi.
- What about Ronson.
- He's been hit.
I'm sending an emergency
evacuation squad.
Well, that'll be too bloody late.
Have they seen us?
Medical Evac for Ronson,
five minutes way.
It's allright?
You'll wait using it.
I wasn't using that one either.
Keep your head down!
Just get clear!
Tanner, which way?
Keep going.
I can direct you from here.
We both know
what's at stake here.
We can not afford
to lose that list.
Yes, ma'am.
Where are they now?
They're on the rooftop
of the grand bazaar.
Take the left, there's a bridge.
You can cut him off.
- What happened?
- They're on the train, ma' am.
What do you mean on the train?
I mean they're on the top
of the train.
Well, get after them,
for God's sake.
He's going out of range.
We've lost tracking.
We are blind here.
- What's going on?
- I'm still with them.
Getting CCTV satellite,
end of question.
What was that?
VW Beetle, I think.
He's uncoupling the cars.
- 007, are you alright?
- Just changing carriages.
What's going on? Report!
It's rather hard
to explain, ma'am.
007 is saying proceed.
This side here isn't much more road.
I do not think I can go any further.
I may have a shot.
It's not clean.
Repeat.
I did not have a clean shot.
There's a tunnel ahead.
I'm gonna lose them.
- Can you get into a better position?
- Negative. There's no time.
Take the shot.
I said, "Take the shot!"
Well, I can't. I may get Bond.
Take the bloody shot.
Agent down.
It's like going
into the headmaster study.
It's new chairman's
just a standard procedure.
Bloody waste of my time,
that's what I'd call it.
I'm sorry to have
to deal with such...
a delicate subject
at our first encounter...
But...
I have to be frank with you.
And that would be a good idea.
The Prime Minister
is concerned.
You can tell him my operatives
are pursuing every avenue.
Have you considered
pulling up the agents?
I've considered every option.
Forgive me,
but that sounds like an evasion.
Forgive me, but why am I here?
Three months ago
you lost the computer drive
containing the identity
of almost every NATO agent
embedded in terrorist organisations
across the globe.
A list which,
in the eyes of our allies,
never existed.
So, if you'll forgive me,
I think you know why you're here.
How you should call it,
a civilian oversight?
No, what we call this is...
a retirement planning.
Your country has only
the highest respect for you
and your many years of service.
When your current posting
is completed,
you'll be awarded to GCMG
with full honors.
Congratulations.
You're firing me?
No, ma'am, I'm here to oversee
the transition period...
leading to your voluntary retirement
in two months' time.
Your successor has yet to be appointed,
so we'll be asking you...
I'm not an idiot, Mallory.
I know I can't do this job
forever.
But I'll be damned if I'm going
to leave the department
in worst shape than I found it.
M... you've had a great run.
- You should leave with dignity.
- Oh to hell with dignity.
I'll leave when the job's done.
Yes?
Now?
Main alert from Q Robson,
trying to decrypt
the stolen hard drive.
We are tracing
the encryption signal.
Localising now.
It's sent here in the UK.
London.
Get to inspect the basis
as soon as possible.
- It's coming from MI6.
- What?
The data back,
it is linking to our network.
Corrupted.
This is behind our firewall.
- We should shut down.
- No, track it.
We have to know
where it's coming from.
Strip the head
and try the source.
How the hell
it entered in our system?
Getting a trace right now.
- It is your computer, ma'am.
- Shut it down.
What is this?
For God's sake!
Just get out of the way.
- Don't you recognise the car?
- Madam...
This is BBC breaking news.
In what now appears to be a major
terrorist attack, in the heart of London.
No one has yet claimed responsibility, for
what sources are calling.
A possible Cyber-Terrorist attack, on the
British Secret Service.
Early reports from the scene, indicate at
least 6 dead.
Many more injured, with victims being
evacuated to local Hospitals.
Within minutes of the explosion
I'm going to find
who ever did this.
Where the hell have you been?
Enjoying death.
007, reporting for duty.
Why didn't you call?
Didn't you get the postcard?
You should try it sometimes.
Get away from it all,
it really lends perspective.
Run out of drink.
Were you awarded, eh?
What it was you said?
Take the bloody shot.
I made a judgement call.
You should have trusted me
to finish the job.
It was the possibility
of losing you...
or the certainty of losing
all those other agents.
I made the only decision I could
and you know it.
I think you've lost your nerve.
What do you expect,
a bloody apology?
You know the rules of the game.
You've been playing it long enough.
- We both have.
- Maybe too long.
Speak for yourself.
Ronson didn't make it, did he?
No.
So, this is it.
We're both played out.
Well, if you believed that,
why did you come back?
Good question.
Because we are under attack...
and you know we need you.
Well, I'm here.
You'll have to be debriefed...
and declared fit
for active service.
You're gonna return to duty
when you've passed the tests.
So take them seriously.
The shower might be an order.
I'm going home and change.
Oh, we sold your flat.
Put your things into storage.
Standard procedure...
on the death of an unmarried
employee with no next of kin.
You should have called.
I'll find a hotel.
Well, you're bloody
will not sleep in here.
They attacked into the
environmental control system
locked out the safety protocols
and have turned on the gas.
Well, that should
have been impossible.
I was told that they have hacked
into our files.
They knew her appointments.
They knew she would be
out of the building.
They weren't targeting her.
They wanted us to see it.
- Where are we, lieutenant?
- New digs.
The old building was declared
strategically vulnerable.
That's putting it mildly.
Their aim is to breach the most secured
computer system in Britain.
So we are at war with them now.
This is part of Churchill's bunker.
Some of these tunnels
are dating back to the 18th century.
Quite fascinating,
if it wasn't for the rats.
- When do I see M?
- Tomorrow, you'll see M...
and Mallory too
if you're lucky.
Who is Mallory?
The new chairman of the
Intelligence and Security Committee.
A charming man, I think.
You and him will really gonna hit it off.
Welcome to the new MI6.
We've have attempted to trace
the computer message, but...
it was sent by an asymmetrical
security algorithm...
with the chance to signal
all over the globe
through thousands
of different servers.
And now that they've accessed
M's code,
it's only a matter of time before
they are able to decrypt the list.
Q branch has been analysing pictures.,
But so far, nothing.
General feeling it's probably
something from her past.
Perhaps when she was
running things in Hong Kong.
- It is no idea what it all means?
- And you believe that?
The truth is we don't have
a clue of what's on the list...
or what they are trying
to do with it.
We can always do this later.
You know what? Let's.
I'd like to start with some
simple words' sensations.
Just tell me the first word
that punch into your head.
For example I might day,
and you might say...
Wasted.
All right.
Gun.
Shot.
- Agent.
- Provocative.
- Woman.
- Provocatrix.
- Heart.
- Target.
- Bird.
- Sky.
- M.
- Bitch.
- Sunlight.
- Swim.
- Moonlight.
- Dance.
- Murder.
- Employment.
- Country.
- England.
Skyfall.
Done.
This is going well.
Get these analysed.
When arrives, on me.
She's ready for you.
I'm sorry. Have we met before?
I am the one
who should say "sorry".
It was only four ribs.
There's nonetheless
vital organs.
Nothing major.
No enough excitement
in Istanbul?
I've been reassigned.
Temporary suspension
from field work.
- Really?
- Something to do with killing 007.
- Well, you gave it your best shot.
- It was hardly my best shot.
I'm sure
I can survive your best.
Time you'll get the chance.
Would you do me a favor,
will you?
If they'll do let you back
out there...
Warn me first.
I'm assisting Gareth Mallory
in the transition...
and then I'll be back
in the field.
- That's what you want?
- Yes, of course.
- This is not for everyone.
- Ah, 007...
It's this way.
In your defense...
a moving target
is much harder to hit.
Then you better keep moving.
The whole office goes off in smoke
and that bloody thing survives.
Your interior decorating tips
have always been appreciated, 007.
007, Gareth Mallory.
I hope I haven't miss anything,
the P.M. does prattle on in a crisis.
- Bond.
- Mallory.
I have just been reviewing
Bond's tests.
Seems you've passed.
By the skin of your teeth.
You're back on active service.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- I'll be outside.
- I only have one question.
Why not stay dead?
You had the perfect way out.
Go and live quietly somewhere.
Not many field agents get to leave this cleanly.
Do you get out in the field much?
You don't need to be an operative
to see the obvious.
It's a young men's game.
Look, you've been seriously injured.
There's no shame in saying
you've lost a step.
The only shame, it would be is
not admitting it until it's too late.
Hire me or fire me.
It's entirely up to you.
If he says he's ready,
he's ready.
Perhaps you can't see at all.
Maybe you will.
What exactly are you implying?
You are sentimental about him.
As long as I am the head
of this department,
I'll choose my own operatives.
Fair enough.
Good luck, 007.
Don't cock it up.
We've analysed the shrapnel fragments.
You're lucky it wasn't a direct hit.
It would have cut you in half.
It's a depleted uranium shell.
Military grade.
Hard to get,
extremely expensive
and only used by a select few.
Recognise anyone?
Him.
Okay, the name's Patrice.
He's a ghost.
No known residence,
or country of origin.
So how do we find him?
Well, luckily we still have one
or two friends left in the CIA.
They're after him for the Yemeni
ambassador's murder.
And they're getting close.
Intel is he's gonna be in Shanghai
in two days time. Probably on a job.
You're to go there
and await further instructions.
If he turns up, he's yours.
Find out who he worked for
and who has the list.
- Then, terminate him for Ronson.
- With pleasure.
Is there anything else
you want to tell me?
No.
Report to the new quarter master
for your documentation.
He hasn't set up shop yet, but
Tanner will put you two together.
Good luck.
Thank you.
007...
You are ready for this?
Yes, ma'am.
I didn't know
Bond passed the tests.
He didn't.
Always makes me feel
a little melancholy.
A grand old warship being
ignominiously hauled away for scrap.
Inevitabilty of time,
don't you think?
What do you see?
A bloody big ship.
Excuse me.
007...
I'm your new Quarter master.
You must be joking.
Why, because I'm not wearing
a lab coat?
Because you still have spots.
My complexion
is hardly relevant.
And your confidence is.
Age is no guarantee
of efficiency.
And youth is no guarantee
of innovation.
Oh, how's it I can do more damage
on my laptop
sitting in my pyjamas before
my first cup of Earl Grey
than you could do
in a year in the field.
So why do you need me?
Every now and then
a trigger has to be pulled.
Or not pulled.
It is hard to know which
in your pyjamas.
- Q...
- 007.
Ticket to Shanghai.
- Documentation and passport.
- Thank you.
And this.
Walter PPKS,  9mm short.
There's a micro dermal sensor
in the grip...
It's been coded to your palm prints,
so only you can fire it.
less of a random killing machine
more of than a personal statement.
And this?
Standard issue radio transmitter.
Activate it and it broadcasts
your location.
Distress signal.
And that's it.
A gun, and a radio.
Not exactly Christmas, is it?
Were you expecting
an exploding pen?
We don't really go in
for that any more.
Good luck out there
in the field.
And please return
the equipment in one piece.
Brave new world.
Who's got the list.
Tell me, who you working for.
Tanner, he's posted
the first five names.
Their cover is blown.
They're in danger.
Get them out now.
Room service.
I didn't order anything.
Not even you.
I have got some
new information.
Aren't you a little over qualified
to be delivering messages?
It's all part
of the learning curve.
And Q is afraid of flying.
Of course he is
So, whoever stole the list
has already decrypted it.
They posted the first five names
on the web.
- It was only a matter of time.
- That should be the start.
They're posting five more
next week and the week after.
It's some kind of
sadistic game.
Cut throat razor.
How very traditional.
Well, I like to do some things
the old-fashion way.
Sometimes the old ways
are the best.
Are you putting your life
in my hands again?
Tanners, already briefed me
on the list...
raising the tantalising question
of what you are really doing here.
My official directive
was to help...
In anyway I can.
Like spying for Mallory.
You know, Mallory
is not as bad as you think.
He is a bureaucrat.
You should do your homework.
Gareth Mallory
was Lieutenant Colonel...
Lieutenant Colonel in Northern
Ireland Herford regiment.
He spent three months
at the hands of the IRA.
So there's more to him
that meets the eye.
We'll see.
Keep still.
This is the tricky part.
Now that's better.
- You look the part now.
- Mmh, mmh.
And what part's that?
Old dog...
new tricks.
Good evening.
Evening.
Don't touch your ear.
I've got three exits.
Lots of blind spots.
I've got them covered.
You look beautiful
in that dress.
You don't scrub up so bad yourself.
It's amazing what one could do
with an extra pair of hands.
You're telling me.
You gamble?
I like a little flutter
now and then...
Who doesn't like
to take chances!
Good evening, sir.
How may I help you?
I'd like to cash this in,
please.
One moment, sir.
Good fortune tonight, sir.
Let's hope so.
With compliments of the house.
Thank you.
Now you can afford
to buy me a drink?
Maybe I'll even stretch
to two.
I'm guessing I got
4 million euros in here.
Not bad.
- I like this game.
- Why don't we play another?
I don't gamble.
I'm not very lucky.
Bit like our friend
in Shanghai.
I've been waiting to see
who'd redeem the chip.
You made such a bold entrance
into our little drama.
Did I over complicate the plot?
Who doesn't appreciate
the occasional twist?
- Mr...
- Bond. James Bond.
Severing, so Mr. Bond...
shall we discuss your next
performance over that drink?
I'd like that.
Are your friends be joining us?
That I'm afraid... is inevitable.
- She's pretty.
- Now, now.
If you like that sort of thing,
I'll keep you posted.
Perfect.
Would you mind if I ask you
a business question?
Depends on the question.
It has to do with... death.
A subject in which
you're well versed.
How would you know that?
Only a certain kind of woman
wears a backless dress
with a Beretta 70
strapped to her thigh.
One could never be
too careful when...
a handsome man in tuxedos
carry Walthers...
I'm correct in assuming
you'll killed Patrice?
Yes.
Might I ask why?
I want to meet your employer.
Be careful what you wish for.
You're scared.
Thank you for the drink...
Mr. Bond.
You put on a good show.
But ever since we sat down
you haven't stop looking
at your bodyguards.
The three of them's a bit excessive.
They're controlling you.
They're not protecting you.
Tattoo on your wrist...
is Macao's sex trade..
You belonged to one of the houses,
what were you, 12
13?
I am guessing he is using this as way out.
Perhaps you thought
you were in love.
But that was a long time ago.
You know nothing about it.
I know when a woman is afraid
and pretending not to be.
How much do you know
about fear?
All there is.
Not like this.
And... not like him.
I can help you.
- I don't think so.
- Let me try.
How?
Bring me to him.
- Can you kill him?
- Yes.
- Will you?
- Someone usually dies.
Perhaps you can.
When I leave,
they're going to kill you.
If you survive,
I'm on the Kimera.
North Harbour...
Berth 7.
We cast off in an hour.
Very nice to have met you,
Mr. Bond.
Good luck.
Good luck with that.
Thank you.
Put it all on red.
It's the circle of life.
Yes?
It's time to cast off.
Right.
I liked you better
without your Baretta.
I feel naked without it.
Good evening.
The controversy surrounding
the Ministry of Defence...
has escalated today
as images of the Hussein
assassination continue to circulate.
We should warn you, some viewers
might find these images disturbing.
Captain Hussein, an MI6 operative
embedded in the Middle East
was one of the five agents exposed
in what is now been considered
the greatest internal security breach
in modern British history.
The Prime Minister continues
to express public support for MI6
while the opposition has taken
the position...
has taken the position where a bunch
of antiquate bloody idiots
are fighting a war we don't understand
and can't possibly win.
Look, three of my agents
are dead already.
Don't embroil me
in politics now.
The Prime Minister
has ordered an inquiry.
You'll have to appear.
Standing in the stocks of midday?
Who is antiquated now?
For Christ sake, listen to yourself.
We are a democracy
and are accountable to the people
we are trying to defend.
We can't keep working
in the shadows.
There are no more shadows.
You don't get this, do you.
Whoever is behind this,
whoever is doing it, he knows us.
He is one of us.
He comes from
the same place as Bond.
The place you say
doesn't exist.
The shadows.
It's not too late.
You could turn back now.
I wouldn't be so sure.
They abandoned it
almost overnight.
He made them think there was
a leak at the chemical plant.
It is amazing the panic you can
cause with a single computer.
He wanted the island.
So he took it.
Does he always get
what he wants?
More than you know.
I'm sorry.
Hello, James. Welcome.
You like the island?
My grandmother had an island.
Nothing to boast off.
You could walk along
within an hour.
But still it was,
it was a paradise for us.
One summer,
we went for a visit...
and discovered the place
had been infested with rats.
They'd come on a fishing boat
and gorged themselves on coconut.
So, how do you get
rats off an island?
My grandmother showed me.
We buried an oil drum
and hinged the lid.
Then we wired the coconut
to the lid as bait...
and the rats will come
for the coconut, and...
They would fall into the drum.
And after a month
you've trapped all the rats.
But what do you do then?
Throw the drum into the ocean?
Burn it? No...
You just leave it...
and they begin to get hungry.
And one by one...
they start eating each other...
until there are only two left,
the two survivors.
And then what,
do you kill them? No.
You take them
and release them into the trees.
And now they don't eat
coconut any more.
Now they only eat rat.
You have changed their nature.
The two survivors.
This is what she made us.
I made my own choices.
You think you did.
That's her genius.
Station H.
Am I right, Hong Kong?
'86 to '97.
Back then, I was her favourite.
And you're not nearly
the agent I was.
I can tell you that.
Just look at you.
Barely held together
by your pills, and your drink.
Don't forget my pathetic
love of country.
You're still clinging to your faith
in that old woman
- when all she does is lie to you.
- She never lied to me.
- No?
- No.
What do you score on your
marksmanship evaluation?
70.
40.
Did she tell you the psychologist
cleared you for duty?
- Yes.
- No.
No.
Medical evaluation; Failed.
Physical evaluation; Failed.
Psychological evaluation, alcohol
and substance addiction indicated.
Pathological rejection
of authority
based on unresolved
childhood trauma.
Subject is not approved
for field duty
and immediate suspension
from service advised.
What is this, if not betrayal?
She send you off to me,
knowing that you're not ready
knowing you will likely die.
Mommy was very bad.
See what she's done to you?
Well, she never tied me
to a chair.
Her loss.
Are you sure this is about M?
It's about her...
and you and me.
You see, we are last two rats.
We can either eat each other.
Or eat everyone else.
How you're trying to remember
your training now?
What's the regulation
to cover this?
Well, first time
for everything.
Yes.
Hmm. What makes you think
this is my first time?
Oh, Mr. Bond...
All the physical stuff's so dull.
So dull.
Chasing spies.
So old-fashioned.
Your knees must be killing you.
England...
The Empire, MI6.
You're living
in the ruins as well.
You just don't know it yet.
At least here there are no
old ladies giving orders...
and no little...
gadgets from those fools
in Q branch.
If you'd want it,
you could pick
your own secret missions...
as I do.
Name it.
You destabilise a multinational
by manipulating stocks. Easy.
Interrupt transmission
from a spy satellite over Kabul.
Done.
Rig an election in Uganda.
All to the highest bidder.
Or a gas explosion in London.
Just point and click.
Well, everyone needs a hobby.
So what's yours?
Resurrection.
Let me show you something.
Tells a story, doesn't it?
They left the island so quickly
that couldn't decide what to take
what to leave, what was important.
And this every day reminds me
to focus on the essentials.
There is nothing...
nothing superfluous in my life.
When a thing is redundant,
it is... eliminated.
Fifty years old McCullan.
A particular favorite of yours,
I understand?
So... what's the toast?
To the women we love?
Darling...
Darling, your lovers are here.
No, no, no, no...
Stand up straight,
keep still...
and whatever you do,
don't lose your head.
Don't lose your head.
Time to redeem
your marksmanship scores.
Let's see.
You can be the first...
to knock the glass
from her head.
And just to be sporting,
I'll let you go first.
Let's see who ends up on top.
Oh, can't believe it.
Can't believe it.
Did you really die that day?
Is there any,
any of the old 007 left?
My turn.
I win. What do you say to that?
A waste of good scotch.
What are you going to do now?
Take me back to her?
All on your own?
Who says I'm on my own?
Latest thing from Q branch.
Called a radio.
You are smaller
than I remembered.
Well, as I bet you remember
you were tall.
Strange, for me it feels just...
like yesterday.
- Are you surprised?
- Not particularly.
But then you always were
a slippery one.
Maybe that's why
you liked me so much.
- You flatter yourself.
- No remorse.
Just as I had imagined.
Regret is unprofessional.
"Regret is unprofessional"...
They kept for five months
in a room with no air.
They tortured me.
And I ain't protected your secrets.
I protected you.
But they made me suffer...
and suffer...
and suffer.
Until I realised...
it was you... who betrayed me.
You betrayed me.
So I had only one thing left.
My cyanide capsule
in my back left molar.
You remember, right?
So I broke the tooth...
and bit into the capsule.
It burned all my insides...
but I didn't die.
Life clung to me
like a disease.
And then...
I understood...
why I had survived.
I needed to look in your eyes
one last time.
Well, I hope it was worth it.
Mr. Silva...
you are going to be transferred
to Belmarsh Prison...
where you will be remanded
in custody...
until the Crown prosecution service
deem you fit to stand trial...
Say my name. Say it.
My real name.
I know you remember it.
Your name is on the memorial wall
of the very building you attacked.
I will have it struck off.
Soon, your past will be
as non-existent as your future.
I'll never see you again.
Did you know
what it does to you?
Hydrogen cyanide?
Look at what you've done,
Mother...
Let's me know what you recover
from his computer.
Has he transmitted the list?
If such, to whom.
- I want this resolved.
- Yes, ma'am.
His name is Tiago Rodriguez.
He was a brilliant agent.
But he started operating beyond
his brief hacking the Chinese.
The hand over was coming up
and they were onto him, so...
I gave him up.
I got six agents in return...
and a peaceful transition.
We should go, ma'am.
Board inquiry begins in 30-minutes.
I want to know
what's on that computer.
Now, looking
at Silva's computer...
it seems to me he's done a number
of slightly unusual things.
He's established
failed saved protocols...
to wipe the memory if there's
any attempt to access certain files.
Only about six people in the world
can program safe guides like that.
Of course there are.
Can you get past them?
I invented them.
Right then.
Let's see what you got for us...
Mr. Silva.
We're in.
Sir...
What do you make of this?
This is Omega site.
Best encrypted level he has.
Looks like obsticated code
to conseal its true purpose.
Security through obscurity.
Ladies and gentlemen,
if I might have order.
I'd like to begin
the proceedings.
We are gathered today
to adjust some important issues
concerning the future
of our national security.
Going somewhere?
So you believe your stewards of MI6
during the recent crisis
has been up to scratch?
Well, I believe we have
apprehended the responsible party
undertaking all
the necessary steps
to ensure that the sensitive
information is contained.
Ugh! Such a job well done.
I'm not saying
it all gone perfectly, but...
You forgive me for not
putting up the bunting.
I find rather difficult to overlook
the monumental security breaches
and dead operatives which you were almost singled handedly responsible.
He's using a polymorphic engine
to mutate the code.
Whenever I try to gain an access,
it changes.
It's like solving the Rubik's cube
that's fighting back.
Stop.
Go in on that.
Granborough.
Granborough Road,
it's an old...
tube station
on the metropolitan line.
Been closed for years.
Use that as a key.
Now, look. It's a map.
It's London.
Subterranean London.
What's going on?
Why the doors open?
Can someone tell me how the hell
he got into our system?
Oh, shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
He hacked us.
Oh, no.
Q...
He's gone.
I'm on the stairwell
below isolation.
Can you read me, Q?
I can hear you.
I'm looking for you.
I've got him.
Tracking the location.
Just keep looking forward.
Enter the next service door
on your right.
If you through that door,
you should be in the tube.
I'm in the tube.
Bond, this isn't an escape.
This was years in the planning.
He wanted us to capture him,
he wanted us to access his computers.
It was all planned.
Blowing up HQ,
only emergency protocols.
And all we have retrieved
down here.
I got all that.
What it's got planned next
it worries me.
The district line is the closest,
there should be
a service door on your left.
Got it.
It won't open.
Of course it will.
Put your back into it.
Why don't you come down here
and put your back into it?
No, it's stuck.
Oh good.
There's a train coming.
Hmm. That's vexing.
I'm through.
I told you.
We've alerted security.
Police are on the way.
Where are you now?
Temple tube station.
Along with half of London.
Oh I see. Here you are.
I know where I am, Q.
Where is he?
Give us a second.
I'm looking for him.
There's too many people.
I can't see him.
Welcome to rush hour
on the tube.
Not something you'd know
much about.
The train's leaving.
Do I get on the train?
Don't get on the train unless
he's on it. Give us a minute.
Do I get on the train.
- Bond...
- What?
Get on the train.
He's keen to get home.
Open the door, please.
Open the door.
Health and Safety. Carry on.
- Where are you?
- Take a wild guess, Q.
He's in disguise, now.
Dressed as a policeman.
Where is he going?
He's going for M.
Tell Tanner.
Get her out of there.
You overlooked
or chosen to ignore
hard evidence...
and consistently,
almost obstantly...
Silva has escaped.
Bond's in pursuit.
We need to get you to a secured
location immediately, ma'am.
Like hell am I going
to show him my back.
Are we straining your attention?
No. Please, Minister. Proceed.
Excuse me.
It's as if you insist on pretending
we still live in the
golden age of espionage,
when human intelligence
was the only resource available.
Well, I find this rather
old-fashioned belief
demonstrates
a reckless disregard for every...
Excuse me, Minister.
I don't mean to interrupt but...
Just for the sake of variety,
might we actually hear
from the witness?
Of course.
Thank you.
I won't miss next time,
Mr. Silva.
Not bad.
Not bad, James,
for a physical wreck.
Why, thank you.
You caught me.
Now, here's your prize.
The latest thing
from my local toy store.
It is called "radio".
I do hope that wasn't for me.
No.
But that is.
Chairman, Ministers...
Today I've repeatedly heard how
irrelevant my department
has become.
Why do we need agents
for Double-O section.
Isn't that all rather quaint?
Well, I suppose I see a different
world than you do.
And the truth is that
what I see frightens me.
I'm frightened because our enemies
are not longer known to us.
They do not exist on the map.
They're not nations.
They are individuals.
But look around you,
who do you fear?
Can you see a face,
a uniform, a flag? No.
Our world is not
more transparent now.
It's more opaque.
It's in the shadows.
That's where we must do battle.
So, before you declare
us irrelevant, ask yourselves:
How safe do you feel?
Just one more thing to say.
My late husband was
a great lover of poetry.
And, um...
I suppose some of it sunk in,
despite my best intentions.
And here today,
I remember this.
I think, from Tennyson.
We are not now that strength
which in old days
moved earth and heaven.
That which we are, we are.
One equal temper
of heroic hearts.
Made weak by time and fate,
but strong in will...
to strive, to seek, to find
and not to yield.
Move.
Move. Move.
007, what the hell
are we doing?
You're kidnapping me.
That would be one way
of looking at it.
Too many people are dying
because of me.
If you wants you,
he's gonna have to come and get you.
We've been one step behind Silva
from the start.
It's time to get out in front
and change the game.
And I'm to be the bait?
All right.
Just us. No one else.
Q, I need help.
I'm tracking the car.
Where are you going?
I got M.
We're about to disappear.
What?
I need you to lay
a trail of breadcrumbs
impossible to follow
for anyone except Silva.
You think you can do it?
I'm guessing
this isn't strictly official.
Not even remotely.
So much for my promising
career in espionage.
Well, I'm not hiding in there
if that's your brilliant plan.
We're changing vehicles.
The trouble with company cars
is they have trackers.
And I suppose that's completely
inconspicuous.
Get in.
It's not very comfortable, is it?
Are you going to complain
the whole way?
Oh, go on and eject me.
See if I care.
Where are we going?
Back in time.
Somewhere we'll have
the advantage.
It's a fine line.
If a breadcrumb's too small
then he might miss it.
Too big and Silva
will smell the rat.
That's what you think, even Silva
will be able to spot that?
He's the only one who could.
Sir...
What are you doing?
We 're just monitoring...
Creating a false tracking signal
for Silva to follow.
Well, sir...
Excellent thinking.
Get them isolated.
Send him on the A9.
It's the direct route.
You can monitor his progress
more accurately
and confirm it
with the traffic cameras.
But what if PM finds out?
Then, we're all buggered.
Carry on.
Is this where you grew up?
Mmhh...
How old were you when they died?
You know the answer to that.
You know the whole story.
Orphans always make
the best recruits.
The storm's coming.
Christ...
No wonder you never came back.
James...
James Bond.
Good God.
You still alive.
Nice to see you too.
M... this is Kincade.
A Game Keeper here since I was a boy.
- Pleased to meet you, Emma.
- Mr. Kincade.
You're a tad late. They sold the place
when they thought you were dead.
Seems they were wrong.
What are you doing here?
Some men are coming to kill us.
We're gonna kill them first.
Then we'd better get ready.
Do we still have a gun room?
They sold the lot to a collector
from Idaho or some such place.
They were shipped out weeks ago.
There's just your father's
old hunting rifle.
We couldn't let that go.
And this is what we've got.
There might be a couple of sticks
of dynamite from the quarry.
But if all else fails,
sometimes...
the old ways are the best.
So, who is it we
supposed to be fighting?
No "we" in it, Kincade.
This is not your fight.
Try and stop me,
you jumped-up little shit.
Now, remember what I taught to you.
Don't let it pull to the left.
I'll do my best.
What did you say
you did for a living?
Emma...
I brought you some things.
The nights get cold here.
Thank you, Mr. Kincade.
It's a beautiful old house.
She is.
And like all great ladies,
she still has her secrets ways.
Let me show you this.
A priest hole.
Yes, from Reformation times.
The tunnel leads
under the moor.
If you get in danger,
this is the place to come.
The night I told him
his parents have died...
he's hid in here for two days.
But he did come out.
He was no boy any more.
We must get on.
I fucked this up, didn't I?
No.
You did your job.
I read your obituary of me.
- And?
- Appalling.
Yeah, I knew you'd hate it.
I did call you 'An example
of the British fortitude.'
That bit was all right.
Are you ready?
I was ready before
you're were born, son.
Welcome to Scotland.
You dropped something?
Are you hurt?
Only my pride.
I never was a good shot.
He's not here,
and he's not here.
Always got to
make an entrance.
You two, go to
the kitchen. Now!
Go behind the yard.
Go to the chapel.
Use the tunnel.
Everyone listen to me.
Don't you dare touch M.
She's mine.
Can your friends
come out and say 'hello'?
Come on. This way.
I always hated this place.
Are you getting warm?
Just make sure Bond is dead.
Now it's me and her.
You see what comes of all
this running around, Mr. Bond?
All this jumping and fighting.
It's exhausting.
Relax.
You need to relax.
Well, mother's calling.
I'll give her
a goodbye kiss for you.
Of course.
It had to be here.
It had to be this way.
Thank you.
- I can't find it, though.
- No.
Please.
Don't.
You're hurt. You're hurt.
What have they done to you?
Free the both of us.
With the same bullet.
Do it.
Do it!
Only you can do it.
Last rat standing.
007.
What took you so long?
Oh, I...
got into some deep water.
I suppose it's...
too late to hang around
and fret.
Well, I'm game if you are.
I did get one thing right.
Wow!
I didn't even know
you could come up here.
I hate to waste a view.
I can see why.
I thought you were going back
out on active service.
I declined.
You said it yourself.
Field works
not for everyone.
If it helps,
I feel a lot safer.
Her will was read today.
She left you this.
Maybe it was her way of telling you
to take a desk job.
Just the opposite.
Thank you.
You know, we've never formally
been introduced.
Oh. My name is Eve.
Eve Moneypenny.
I look forward to our time together,
Miss Moneypenny.
Me too.
I'm sure we will have
one or two close shaves.
Good morning, 007.
- Good morning, Tanner.
- He will see you now.
How's the arm, sir?
What?
Oh, it's fine.
It will get better.
All pretty shocking for someone
unused to field work.
So, 007...
Lots to be done.
Are you ready
to get back to work?
With pleasure, M.
With pleasure.